Guide to the Institute for Health Policy Studies - AIDS Resource Program Records
UCSF Library & CKM
- San Francisco City and County, 1983-1989; 1993; Series 2; 1 carton 46 folders
  - AIDS Service Delivery System (Box:folder 2:55-3:9)
    - Hunters Point Project, 1988 (Box:folder 2:66)
    - Jewish Family and Children's Services, 1987 (Box:folder 2:67)
    - Kara, 1987 (Box:folder 2:68)
    - KWIC-FAN (Kapuna West Inter-City Child and Family AIDS Network), 1986-1987 (Box:folder 2:69)
    - Latino AIDS Project, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 2:70)
    - Living/Dying Project, n.d. (Box:folder 2:71)
    - Multicultural Prevention Resource Center (Box:folder 2:72-P:1)
      - Folder, 1987 (Box:folder 2:72)
      - 3 Oversize Posters, 1987 (Box:folder P:1)
    - Operation Concern, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 2:73)
    - Our Place at Trinity, n.d. (Box:folder 2:74)
    - Peter Claver Community, 1988 (Box:folder 2:75)
    - Project Inform, 1986-1987 (Box:folder 2:76)
    - Project Open Hand, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 2:77)
    - Rest Stop, n.d. (Box:folder 2:78)
    - San Francisco AIDS Foundation, 1985-1989; 1993 (Box:folder 3:1-3:2)
    - Shanti Project, 1985-1989 (Box:folder 3:3)
    - Stop AIDS Project, 1986-1987 (Box:folder 3:4-3:5)
    - Women's AIDS Network, 1986-1989 (Box:folder 3:6-3:9)
  - City and County Agencies/Commissions (Box:folder 3:10-3:43)
    - City AIDS Budget, 1987 (Box:folder 3:10)
    - County AIDS Budget, 1987; 1989 (Box:folder 3:11)
    - Health Care Services, 1986; 1988 (Box:folder 3:12)
    - Health Commission (Box:folder 3:13-3:21)
      - Calendars, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 3:13-3:14)
      - Minutes (Box:folder 3:15-3:20)
        - March-December 1987 (Box:folder 3:15)
        - April 1986-January 1987 (Box:folder 3:16)
        - 1988 (Box:folder 3:17)
        - August-December 1989 (Box:folder 3:18)
        - January-July 1989 (Box:folder 3:19)
        - 1990 (Box:folder 3:20)
      - Hearings on AIDS, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 3:21)
    - Health Resources and Services Administration AIDS Proposal, 1986 (Box:folder 3:22)
    - History of AIDS Service Delivery System, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 3:23)
    - HIV Antibody Testing - Alternative Test Sites, 1986-1987 (Box:folder 3:24)
    - Human Rights Commission, 1989; n.d. (Box:folder 3:25)
    - Public Health Services Hospital, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 3:26)
    - RWJ (Robert Woods Johnson) AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1986 (Box:folder 3:27)
    - Department of Public Health (Box:folder 3:28-3:33)
      - General Information, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 3:28)
      - AIDS Activity Office, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 3:29)
      - AIDS Grand Rounds, 1987-1989 (Box:folder 3:30)
      - Bureau of Communicable Disease Control, 1986 (Box:folder 3:31)
      - Community Substance Abuse Services - Overview, 1987 (Box:folder 3:32)
      - Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) San Francisco AIDS/ARC Demonstration Project, 1987 (Box:folder 3:33)
    - Epidemiology of AIDS (Box:folder 3:35-37)
      - Intravenous (IV) Drug Abuse, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 3:35)
      - Sexually Transmitted Diseases, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 3:36-37)
    - San Francisco General Hospital (Box:folder 3:38-43)
      - General Information, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 3:38)
      - AIDS Census, 1984 (Box:folder 3:39)
      - Division of AIDS Activities, 1985-1987 (Box:folder 3:40)
      - Utilization Review (Challenges to MediCal denials), 1985-1986; RESTRICTED (Box:folder *15:5)
      - County-Community Physicians Consortium, 1985-1986 (Box:folder 3:41)
      - Ward 5A/5B, 1984-1986 (Box:folder 3:42)
      - Ward 86, 1985-1986 (Box:folder 3:43)
    - UCSF AIDS Activities (Box:folder 4:1-9)
      - General, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 4:1)
      - AIDS Clinical Research Center (Box:folder 4:2-3)
        - Grant Proposal/Renewal, 1985-1986 (Box:folder 4:2)
        - General, 1985; 1988 (Box:folder 4:3)
      - Division of AIDS Activities, 1987; n.d. (Box:folder 4:4)
      - AIDS Resource Directory, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 4:5)
      - AIDS History (Archives) Project, 1987 (Box:folder 4:6)
      - School of Dentistry, 1987 (Box:folder 4:7)
      - School of Nursing, [1984]-1986 (Box:folder 4:8)
      - University-wide Task Force on AIDS, 1983-1987 (Box:folder 4:9)
- States and Countries, 1983-1989; Series 3; 1 carton 37 folders
  This series consists of files about AIDS programs in a number of states within the United States and in several other countries. It includes newspapers clippings, grant requests, correspondence, reports, statistics, publicity materials, and publications.
  Many of the State folders include grant proposals to the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation's (RJW) AIDS Health Services Program (AHSP). Most of these are full proposals with attachments, in some cases only the narrative part of the grant is included. Also included in this series are reports and other items such as the "Report to the County Commissioners, Mayor and the City Council" from the East Metro AIDS Task Force of St. Paul, Minnesota. Correspondence includes letters soliciting materials, thanking agencies for materials, arranging visits to the IHPS, reviews of grant proposals, and more. The California files are from southern California and consist primarily of RJW grant proposals. As might be expected the largest number of folders are for New York State, covering a number of different cities, organizations, and subjects. Kentucky, Louisiana, Maine, New Hampshire, and Utah are some of the single folder states.
  The Country files section begins with folders for Africa and Asia, though many individual countries from these two continents are also represented. Another multi-country regional designation used was Scandinavia, which includes materials on Sweden and Finland; the Netherlands has a separate folder. The Puerto Rico folder, though included with the other Countries files, contains RWJ AHSP proposal the same as many of the State folders. Many of the Country files consist solely of newspaper clippings and several contain only a single sheet of material. The Australia folder contains several issues of an Australian AIDS publication.
  Most of the states and countries are represented by a single file. States with multiple folders are subdivided by city and/or organization or project. The first folder of the series contains information from the United States Conference of Mayors, followed by states in alphabetical order and then by Countries in alphabetical order.
  - U.S. Conference of Mayors, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 4:10)
  - Arizona, 1987 (Box:folder 4:11)
  - California (Box:folder 4:12-16)
    - Anaheim - RJW Grant Proposal, 1986 (Box:folder 4:12)
    - Los Angeles (Box:folder 4:13-16)
      - AIDS Project Los Angeles, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 4:13)
      - Epidemiology of AIDS, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 4:14)
      - A Proposal for the Support and Development of AIDS Services in Los Angeles by AIDS Project Los Angeles, June 16, 1986 (Box:folder 4:15)
      - Los Angeles County Department of Health Services, 1987 (Box:folder 4:16)
  - Colorado (Box:folder 4:17-19)
    - Boulder County Health Department - AIDS Prevention Program, 1986 (Box:folder 4:17)
    - Denver, RWJ AIDS Health Services Program Proposal, 1986 (Box:folder 4:18)
    - Law re: Seropositivity Disclosure, 1987 (Box:folder 4:19)
  - Florida (Box:folder 4:20-22)
    - Epidemiology of AIDS, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 4:20)
    - Miami and Sarasota, 1988 (Box:folder 4:21)
    - West Palm Beach RWJ AIDS Health Services Program Proposal, 1986 (Box:folder 4:22)
  - Georgia/Atlanta includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Program Proposal, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 4:23)
  - Illinois (Box:folder 4:24-28)
    - AIDS Legislation, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 4:24)
    - AIDS Service Delivery System, 1987; n.d. (Box:folder 4:25)
    - Alcoholism and Drug Dependence Association, 1988 (Box:folder 4:26)
    - Chicago (Box:folder 4:27-28)
      - General, 1988 (Box:folder 4:27)
      - RWJ AIDS Health Services Program/Chicago AIDS Project, 1986 (Box:folder 4:28)
  - Kentucky, 1988 (Box:folder 4:29)
  - Louisiana / New Orleans RWJ AIDS Health Services Program Proposal, 1986; 1988 (Box:folder 4:30)
  - Maine, n.d. (Box:folder 4:31)
  - Maryland / Baltimore 2RWJ AIDS Health Services Program Proposals, 1986; 1988 (Box:folder 4:32)
  - Massachusetts (Box:folder 4:33-35)
    - General Statewide (IVDU, AIDS Library, Policies), 1987-1988 (Box:folder 4:33)
    - Boston (Box:folder 4:34-35)
      - Boston AIDS Consortium, 1988 (Box:folder 4:34)
      - RWJ AIDS Program "AIDS Link" Proposal, 1986 (Box:folder 4:35)
  - Michigan (Box:folder 4:36-37)
    - Detroit - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal [cover letter and appendices only], 1986-1988 (Box:folder 4:36)
    - Wayne County, 1988 (Box:folder 4:37)
  - Minnesota (Box:folder 4:38-40)
    - Department of Public Health, 1988; n.d. (Box:folder 4:38)
    - St. Paul - East Metro AIDS Task Force (Box:folder 4:39-40)
      - Report to the County Commissioners, Mayor and City Council - Draft and Final, 1988 (Box:folder 4:39)
      - AIDS Services and AIDS Education In Dakota, Ramsey, and Washington County, 1987 (Box:folder 4:40)
  - New Hampshire [clippings], 1987-1988 (Box:folder 4:41)
  - New Jersey (Box:folder 4:42-45)
    - Newark (Department of Health), 1987 (Box:folder 4:42)
    - State Department of Health (Box:folder 4:43-44)
      - AIDS in New Jersey, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 4:43)
      - RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal: Newark and Jersey City, 1986 (Box:folder 4:44)
    - RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal - Project Caring, 1986 (Box:folder 4:45)
  - New York (Box:folder 4:46-47, 5:1-13)
    - State Department of Health (Box:folder 4:46-47, 5:1)
      - General, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 4:46)
      - Visit to San Francisco Department of Health, 1985 (Box:folder 4:47)
      - Request for Applications/Request for Proposals, 1985-1986 (Box:folder 5:1)
    - General, 1986-1987 (Box:folder 5:2)
    - Training Institute Narcotic and Drug Research - CARE (Comprehensive AIDS Risk-Reduction Effort, 1986? (Box:folder 5:3)
    - Rochester and Finger Lakes Region AIDS Action Plan, 1985-1986 (Box:folder 5:4)
    - Nassau County - RWJ AID Health Services Application, 1986 (Box:folder 5:5)
    - New York City (Box:folder 5:6-5:13)
      - AIDS Prevention and Education, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:6)
      - AIDS Service Delivery Program, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 5:7)
      - Epidemiology of AIDS, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 5:8)
      - Hospitals Response to AIDS, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 5:9)
      - IV Drug Use, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:10)
      - RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposals (Box:folder 5:11-5:13)
        - AIDS Services Delivery Consortium for New York City, 1986 (Box:folder 5:11)
        - Lower Manhattan AIDS Consortium Comprehensive AIDS Program, 1986 (Box:folder 5:12)
        - New York City Interagency Community-based AIDS Services Project, 1986 (Box:folder 5:13)
  - North Dakota, 1987 (Box:folder 5:14)
  - Oklahoma, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:15)
  - Oregon, 1988 (Box:folder 5:16)
  - Pennsylvania (Box:folder 5:17-18)
    - General, 1988-1989 (Box:folder 5:17)
    - Philadelphia - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1986; n.d. (Box:folder 5:18)
  - Tennessee, 1988 (Box:folder 5:19)
  - Texas (Box:folder 5:20-22)
    - Funding Report, 1987 (Box:folder 5:20)
    - Dallas - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1986; 1988 (Box:folder 5:21)
    - Houston - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 5:22)
  - Utah, 1986 (Box:folder 5:23)
  - Virginia, 1988 (Box:folder 5:24)
  - Washington, D.C. - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 5:25)
  - Washington / Seattle-King County - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1986; 1988 (Box:folder 5:26)
  - Africa [see also individual countries], 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:27)
  - Asia [see also individual countries], 1985-1988 (Box:folder 5:28)
  - Australia, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 5:29)
  - Brazil, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:30)
  - Canada, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:31)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1987 (Box:folder 5:32)
  - China, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:33)
  - Cuba, 1987-1989 (Box:folder 5:34)
  - Egypt, 1986 (Box:folder 5:35)
  - France, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:36)
  - Gabon, 1988 (Box:folder 5:37)
  - Great Britain, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 5:38)
  - Greece, 1987 (Box:folder 5:39)
  - Haiti, 1986-1987 (Box:folder 5:40)
  - Honduras, 1987 (Box:folder 5:41)
  - Hungary, 1987 (Box:folder 5:42)
  - Italy, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:43)
  - Ivory Coast, 1987 (Box:folder 5:44)
  - Japan, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:45)
  - Kenya, 1987 (Box:folder 5:46)
  - Korea, 1987 (Box:folder 5:47)
  - Mexico, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:48)
  - Middle East, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:49)
  - The Netherlands, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 5:50)
  - Nicaragua, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:51)
  - Niger, 1987 (Box:folder 5:52)
  - Nigeria, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:53)
  - Philippines, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:54)
  - Poland, 1987 (Box:folder 5:55)
  - Puerto Rico - San Juan - includes RWJ AIDS Health Services Proposal, 1986; 1988 (Box:folder 5:56)
  - Rwanda, 1987 (Box:folder 5:57)
  - Scandinavia [Sweden and Finland], 1984-1987 (Box:folder 5:58)
  - South Africa, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:59)
  - Switzerland, 1985; 1988 (Box:folder 5:60)
  - Tahiti, 1987 (Box:folder 5:61)
  - Tanzania, 1986 (Box:folder 5:62)
  - Thailand, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:63)
  - Uganda, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:64)
  - Uruguay, 1987 (Box:folder 5:65)
  - U.S.S.R., 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:66)
  - West Germany, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 5:67)
  - Yugoslavia, 1987 (Box:folder 5:68)
  - Zaire, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 5:69)
  - Zambia, 1987 (Box:folder 5:70)
  - Zimbabwe, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 5:71)
- United States (Federal Government), 1976; 1983-1990; Series 4; 1 carton 30 folders
  This series contains materials by or about different federal government level AIDS and/or AIDS-related programs. These consist of items concerning legislation, budgeting, hearings, publications, correspondence, and news reports from both the legislative and executive branches of the United States government, as well as various administrative departments.
  The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) files, which include materials on the U.S. Public Health Service and the Surgeon General, make up the largest portion of this series. The Congressional files make up the next largest subset. At the beginning of the series are two are runs of two different informational publications: The National Health Policy Forum's weekly Issue Briefs which were issued by George Washington University and the CDC Weekly Surveillance Reports on AIDS. The Administration files contain folders on the Attorney General and the Office of the President. Information on the President's Commission on AIDS can be found in the Federal Policies/Responses to AIDS files along with information from the General Accounting Department (GAO) on the Federal AIDS Budget. The Department of Education folder contains newspaper clippings about Secretary of Education, William Bennett. There are also single folders on the Social Security Administration, the Department of State - Agency for International Development (consists RFP's), Federal Health Budget, Health Status in United States, United States Health Care System (clippings) and the Epidemiology of AIDS (see also Series V: Subject Files).
  Of special interest are the DHHS files which include testimony from Secretary Heckler, materials from the "America Responds to AIDS" campaign, and a "Testing File" which includes correspondence. Also included in this category is information on the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) AIDS Services demonstration programs in New York, San Francisco, Los Angeles, & Miami - including correspondence, notes, grant applications, the original RFP and a blank Grant application. The U.S. Public Health Service (PHS) files are included with the DHHS files (the Budget folder includes information on testimony to the PHS), as are folders on the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the National Institute of Health, the National Institute of Mental Health, National Center for Health Service Research, and the Task Force on AIDS.
  The United States Congress files include folders on both Senate and House hearings. These files contain copies of testimony as well as clippings and other items. Other Congressional files contain correspondence, notes, text of bills and other items, as well as numerous newspaper clippings.
  Also of interest is the Feb.1986 publication Disability Evaluation Under Social Security within the Social Security Administration files. The Federal Policies/Responses to AIDS folder includes the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Science's "Recommendations to President-Elect George Bush., President's Commission on AIDS." The final folder in the series contains information on the 1988 Presidential candidates and AIDS. Materials from or about the Congressional Office of Technology Assessment (OTA) within the Senate files and the OTA section within this series. OTA material can also be found in the Series V: Subject Files.
  - National Health Policy Forum - Issue Briefs - all runs incomplete (Box:folder 6:1-3)
    - Briefs #449-#473, 1986-1987 (Box:folder 6:1)
    - Briefs #474-#518, 1987-1989 (Box:folder 6:2)
    - Briefs #520-#550, 1989-1990 (Box:folder 6:3)
  - CDC - AIDS Weekly Surveillance Report (Box:folder 6:4-8)
    - July 30,1984 - December 29,1986 (Box:folder 6:4)
    - January 5 - May 25,1987 (Box:folder 6:5)
    - June 1 - December 28,1987 (Box:folder 6:6)
    - January 4 - July 25,1988 (Box:folder 6:7)
    - August 8,1988 - January 23,1989 (Box:folder 6:8)
  - Administration (Box:folder 6:9-11)
    - Attorney General, 1987 (Box:folder 6:9)
    - Domestic Policy Council, 1987 (Box:folder 6:10)
    - Office of the President, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 6:11)
  - US Congress (Box:folder 6:12-22)
    - Federal Budget - Ad Hoc Task Force on AIDS, 1987 (Box:folder 6:12)
    - AIDS Budget Recommendations, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 6:13)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box:folder 6:14)
    - Senate AIDS Hearings, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 6:15)
    - AIDS Hearings - House of Representatives, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 6:16-17)
    - AIDS Legislation (Box:folder 6:18-19)
      - Senate Bills, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 6:18)
      - House of Representatives Bills, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 6:19)
    - Nancy Pelosi and the AIDS Health Care Financing Act of 1988 (Box:folder 6:20)
    - Individual Legislators, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 6:21)
    - Library of Congress - Congressional Research Service - Issue Brief # IB83162, 1983 (Box:folder 6:22)
  - Department of Education [Bennett] (Box:folder 6:23)
  - Department of Health & Human Services (Box:folder 6:24-37, 7:1-15)
    - Office of the Secretary, 1984-1987 (Box:folder 6:24)
    - National Institute on Drug Abuse, 1987 (Box:folder 6:25)
    - Center for Disease Control (Box:folder 6:26-27)
      - America Responds to AIDS Campaign, 1987 (Box:folder 6:26)
      - Testing, Policies, etc., 1976; 1985-1987 (Box:folder 6:27)
    - Food and Drug Administration, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 6:28)
    - Health Care Financing Administration (Box:folder 6:29-30)
      - Medicaid, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 6:29)
      - Medicare, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 6:30)
    - Health Resources and Services Administration (Box:folder 6:31-7:1)
      - AIDS Service Demonstration Programs (Box:folder 6:31-35)
        - New York, 1986 (Box:folder 6:31)
        - San Francisco, 1986 (Box:folder 6:32)
        - Los Angeles, 1986 (Box:folder 6:33)
        - Miami, 1986 (Box:folder 6:34)
      - General Information, 1986 (Box:folder 6:35)
      - AIDS Regional Education and Training Center Grants (Box:folder 6:36-37, 7:1)
        - Request for Proposals and Administration Information, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 6:36)
        - Grant Application and Supplementary Materials, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 6:37)
        - San Francisco Cooperative Grant Preparation, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 7:1)
    - National Institute on Drug Abuse, 1986 (Box:folder 7:2)
    - National Institute of Health, 1984-1988 (Box:folder 7:3)
    - National Institute of Mental Health, 1988 (Box:folder 7:4)
    - National Center for Health Statistics - Health Promotion and Disease Prevention, 1985 (Box:folder 7:5)
    - National Center for Health Service Research, 1988-1989 (Box:folder 7:6)
    - Public Health Service (Box:folder 7:7-11)
      - AIDS: A Public Health Challenge Vol. 2 (Chapters 6-10), 1988 (Box:folder 7:7)
      - AIDS Budget Recommendations, Criticism, 1984-1987 (Box:folder 7:8)
      - Testimony by Alan Harris, Regional Coordinator Region IX, January/February 1988 (Box:folder 7:9)
      - Reports - Review of the Public Health Services Response to AIDS, 1985-1988 (Box:folder 7:10)
      - Prevention Report, 1988 (Box:folder 7:11)
    - Surgeon General (Box:folder 7:12-13)
      - Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 7:12)
      - Reports/Pamphlets, 1988 (Box:folder 7:13)
    - Task Force on AIDS, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 7:14)
  - Social Security Administration, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 7:15)
  - Department of State - Agency for International Development - RFPs, 1987 (Box:folder 7:16)
  - Epidemiology of AIDS, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 7:17)
  - Federal Policies (Box:folder 7:18-22)
    - Federal Policies/Responses to AIDS, 1983-1988 (Box:folder 7:18)
    - President's Commission on AIDS / Watkins Commission (Box:folder 7:19-21)
      - Clippings, 1988; 1987 (Box:folder 7:19-20)
      - Reports, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 7:21)
    - GAO (General Accounting Office) Views on Administration AIDS Budget Proposals, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 7:22)
  - Federal Health Budget, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 7:23)
  - U.S. Health Care System - Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box:folder 7:24)
  - Health Status in U.S., 1986-1987 (Box:folder 7:25)
  - Office of Technology Assessment (Box:folder 7:26-29)
    - "The Costs of AIDS and other HIV Infections", 1987 (Box:folder 7:26)
    - AIDS-Related Issues - Staff Paper 2 and Paper 4, 1988 (Box:folder 7:27)
    - "How Effective is AIDS Education" - Staff Paper 3, 1988 (Box:folder 7:28)
    - Medical Testing and Health Insurance, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 7:29)
  - 1988 Presidential Candidates and AIDS, 1987-1988 (Box:folder 7:30)
- Subject Files, 1979-1989; Series 5; 5 cartons 1 box 12 folders
  By far the largest series in the collection, the "Subject Files" include everything from newspapers clippings to correspondence and published works to working documents and handwritten notes. Arranged alphabetically by "Subject" these files represent the breadth of materials, topics of interest and research done by the IHPS-ARP. Many of the topics of these folders overlap with each other and with other parts of the collection. Some of these materials are exact duplicates of materials found elsewhere, but were left where they were to illustrate that the IHPS-ARP classified them under multiple categories. Some subjects are also covered more than once within the "subject" classifications. For example: materials on IV drug users are filed under the IV Drug Use and under Risk Groups - IV Drug Users, as well as related terms such as Substance Abuse and Needle exchange. Related materials may also be found in other series as well. Individual topics can be represented by everything from a couple of newspaper clippings in a single folder to multiple folders including original materials. For preservation reasons, newspaper clippings have been segregated to the front of each folder in which they appear, with original items being found further back in the folders.